在上一集里
Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
只有领袖之力能唤醒它！
It will only respond to the power of a Prime!
探测器发现了另一个铁堡信号！
Our sensors detected a second Iacon-locator beacon.
我去
I'll go.
烟幕选择的汽车形态 车门上印着一对招摇过市的38
Smokescreen chooses a vehicle mode with screaming double "38S" on the doors
很容易被辨识出来
making him an easy target.
我没法假装我一点也不担心杰克的安危
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't more than concerned about Jack's safety.
星辰剑…
The Star Saber
卓天越铸造的神兵利器！
a legendary weapon forged by Solus Prime.
我们霸天虎…迎来了最黑暗的时刻
We Decepticons now face our darkest hour.
我收到了一条信息…
I am receiving a message.
谁发来的？
From who?
钛师傅
Alpha Trion.
请原谅 威震天陛下
Forgive me, lord Megatron.
属下丝毫不敢质疑您英明的战略性撤退
While I do not question the wisdom of our tactical retreat
现在 属下已准备好带领人马去反击汽车人了！
know that I am fully prepared to lead the troops in a counterattack against the Autobots.
反击？
Counterattack?
你难道没看见
Perhaps you failed to notice Optimus Prime
擎天柱仅一击就切开了整座山吗？
cleave an entire mountain with a single blow.
只要有星辰剑在手
With the Star Saber in his possession
我的宿敌只须抬抬胳膊就能把我们斩尽杀绝！
my enemy can obliterate us all with a wave of his hand!
我必须让力量的天平重新向我们倾斜！
I must find a way to tip the balance of power back in our favor.
我们不也拥有一个强大的先祖遗物么？
Do we not also possess a powerful relic of the ancients?
的确如此 那是卓天越之锤
Indeed... the forge of Solus Prime.
但如果不是握在领袖的手上 那东西就毫无用处…
But it is useless, except in the hand of a Prime.
若我有一只领袖之手
But I might wield that power
或许也能支配那神力
if I were to control such a hand!
擎天柱 钛师傅说了什么？
Optimus, what is Alpha Trion saying?
我真希望能在更好的境况下与你相会 擎天柱
I wish that I could meet you under better circumstances, Optimus Prime
但我担心铁堡无法撑过霸天虎的下一轮进攻了
but I fear that Iacon will not withstand the next Decepticon assault.
于是你传话于我
So you speak to me
穿越时空的岁月？
from across the ages.
如果你听到了这则讯息
If you are listening to this message
那么我相信此刻你已经得到了星辰剑
then I take solace that you now possess the Star Saber.
我确信你已经推断出了\N这些塞博特恩的遗物和霸天虎的武器
I am certain that you have deduced how these Cybertronian relics and Decepticon weapons
何以出现在如此遥远的世界
came to be found on such a remote world.
没错 是我将它们传送过去的
Indeed, I transported them there
此举并非是防止它们落入敌手
not so much to keep them far from Megatron's hands
而是将它们传授与你…
but to ensure that they reach yours.
正如你长期以来所怀疑的
As you may have long suspected
“原始天尊圣约”不仅记载了过去 还能预示未来
the Covenant of Primus records events of the future as well as the past.
根据我的不完全解读
My imperfect understanding of its runes
我对未来的景象得以惊鸿一瞥
affords me a shadowy glimpse of what is to come.
圣约中的一页预言道 你 擎天柱
The Covenant's pages foretold that you, Optimus Prime
将会前往一颗娇小但意义重大的星球
would journey to the small, but significant planet
并在那里谱写反霸天虎战争的新篇章
and there engage in a crucial chapter in the war against the Decepticons.
我既无法得知那场战争的前因
I know neither the nature of the battle
也不晓得后果 我只能寄望于
nor its outcome, I only hope that
这些先祖遗物能够在你\N最需要的时候助汽车人一臂之力
these relics of the ancients will aid the Autobots in your time of need.
最重要的是
Of utmost importance
再过不久
in a few moments
我就会将最后一批遗物传送出去
I will launch the last of the relics
这批意义最为重大 同时也是最强大的…
the most significant and powerful of them all.
放松 擎天柱
Easy, Optimus.
话说 钛师傅有没有跟我打招呼？
So, did Alpha try and ask about me?
那信息到底讲了什么？
What was the message?
找到最后四个铁堡遗物是我们的当务之急
It is paramount that we recover the final four Iacon relics...
它们是“终极之钥”…
the Omega keys.
钥匙？
Keys?
能打开什么？
To what?
我们的故乡涅重生的关键…
To the regeneration of our home planet.
地球的月亮不过是一块荒芜的石块 您说是么？
Earth's Moon is a barren rock, is it not?
的确如此 骇翼
Indeed, Dreadwing.
但月球并不是我们的目的地
But the Moon is not our destination.
一座太空桥？
A space bridge?
我们独有的太空桥
Our very own
自从汽车人在地球上发现了它 我们就将它搬至此处
relocated here after the Autobots discovered its whereabouts on Earth.
月球的背面能够掩人耳目 避开那些喜欢窥探的人类
The dark side of the Moon is hidden from prying human eyes.
更重要的是
and, more importantly
汽车人也无法到达这里
well out of the Autobots' reach.
来吧 骇翼！
Come, Dreadwing!
我带你去一个地方 就在银河系里
We shall travel to the one place in the galaxy
我们将在那里得到能够击败擎天柱的东西！
which may provide us with a means of defeating Optimus Prime.
打好行囊
Pack your gear.
我们就要回塞博特恩了！
We're going back to Cybertron!
哈哈哈 信不信由你 大黄蜂！
Hahahaha. Well, believe it now, Bumblebee.
咱终于能回到文明社会了！
Civilization at last.
可我才刚初来乍到啊！
But I just got here.
还记得油浴吗？
Remember oil baths?
回去后我要做的第一件事\N就是在油里泡上整整一个太阳周期！
The first thing I'm gonna do planetside is soak for an entire solar cycle.
哈哈哈 我都等不及想告诉神子了！
Hahaha. I can't wait to tell Miko.
还有…杰克
And Jack.
擎天柱 钥匙是用来开门的
Uh... Optimus, keys open doors.
那东西真能让整个星球复活吗？
Can they really revive an entire planet?
我并不太清楚这些“终极之钥”的原理
While I am unfamiliar with the lore of these Omega keys
但钛师傅知晓其中的秘密
Alpha Trion knew many secrets
我们的先祖拥有许多神奇的科技
and the ancients possessed technology
在我们的现代科学中早已失传
that has long been lost to what we consider modern science.
故乡比我想象的还要颓败和荒芜…
The devastation to our home world is worse than I remember.
诅咒那些该死的汽车人！
Curse the Autobots to the pit!
尽管还不清楚功能和原理
Whatever their function
但有一件事可以确定
this much is certain...
那就是只有集齐四枚终极之钥 才能让塞博特恩复苏
we cannot restore Cybertron without all four Omega keys in our possession.
换言之 我们绝不能让威震天得到任何一枚！
Which means we can't afford to lose a single one to Megatron.
钛师傅的讯息里还剩下四组加密坐标
Four sets of coordinates from Alpha Trion remain encrypted.
我们可以推断出那就是终极之钥的位置
It is logical to conclude that each corresponds to the location of one of the Omega keys.
我一定会竭尽全力把它们全部破译
I must not waver until I decode them all.
故乡的未来就靠它了！
The future of our home world depends on it.
一座古墓！
A tomb.
据说这座古墓里长眠着一位元祖领袖！
One known to contain the remains of Primes.
拜托 别告诉我你不愿亵渎圣地！
Please tell me you're not averse to desecration.
我不过是有股情感在心头涌动而已
It is just that being in such a place evokes powerful emotions
想起了我孪生兄弟的悲惨命运…
considering the fate of my twin.
那你就更应该来到这里
Then you should delight in our purpose here
为了给天震
to exact our revenge of Skyquake
和所有牺牲的同胞复仇
and of all our fallen brethren.
你需要一个合适的方式携带这把利刃…
You shall require a more practical means of carrying such a blade.
我知道这听起来有些滑稽 但是…
I feel funny saying this, but
我不确定我是否真的愿意回去
I'm not sure I want to go back.
谁能想到呢 我们已经习惯新家的生活了
Who knew we'd ever get so used to our new home?
是啊 我永远都不想离开神子
Yeah. I don't think I'd ever want to leave Miko.
我们在这儿交到了朋友…和家人
We've made friends here, family.
我们不是还能常常…发短信嘛！
We could always... text them.
再说
Besides
咱们打了这么久 我都不知道自己还会不会干些别的了
been fighting for so long, I don't know if I can do anything else.
你可以再回去当建筑工人
You can go back into construction.
先祖的神力或许能让塞博特恩的核心重焕生机
The power of the ancients may breathe life back into Cybertron's core
但被战火摧毁的城市还是需要有人来重建的！
but our war-ravaged cities will surely require rebuilding.
我觉得暂时先别想这些旅行计划了
I wouldn't make any travel plans just yet.
咱们还得先找到终极之钥 要赶在虎子之前
We still have to locate these Omega keys and secure them before the 'Cons do.
那还不是手到擒来啊
Yeah, like that'll be a problem.
擎天柱可是有星辰剑在手呢！
Optimus has the Star Saber now.
威震天的末日指日可待了！
Megatron's end is in sight.
我当然可以 威震天陛下…
Yes, I can do it, lord Megatron
如果您确定这就是您想要的
if you're certain that's what you really want.
我比任何时候都坚决 医官
Like nothing I've ever desired before, Doctor.
开始催眠…
I shall induce stasis.
不！我要亲眼所见
No! I wish to bear witness
你将我的新肢体接驳上来
as you attach my new appendage.
我开始了
Coming up.
汽车人 我已经破译了第一个坐标
Autobots, I have decoded the first set of the final four coordinates.
大家分成小组 以防我在第一组回来之前
Divide into teams in the event
就破译出了第二个坐标
that I'm able to decode another before the first team returns.
我要进第一组！谁想一起来？
I'm on team one. Who's with me?
我来吧
I'll go.
您先请 长官
After you, sir...
…女士
ma'am...
…指挥官？
... commander?
这组合会很有趣…
This should be interesting.
啊 哈哈哈哈 太好了…
Uh. Ha ha ha ha hahaha. Yes.
终于 领袖的力量现在属于我了！
At long last, the power of the Primes belongs to me!
第一组到达
First one is here.
没有信号
No locator beacon
也就是说遗物仍然被埋藏着
which means the relic's still buried
就在…那里！
right about... there.
卓天越之锤
The forge of Solus Prime
拥有能将原材料打造成任何东西的神力？
possesses the ability to create anything from raw material.
而现在
And in this case
那原材料可是一大块儿黑暗能量啊
said raw material would be a big hunk of Dark Energon.
那个 阿尔茜 我还欠你一份歉意
Uh, Arcee, I-I owe you an apology.
我从来没想过让杰克置身险境
I never meant to endanger Jack.
人类是很脆弱的 我现在彻底明白这一点了
Humans squish easily. I get that now.
这不光是因为杰克
This isn't just about Jack.
领袖卫队再也承受不起任何牺牲了
Team Prime can't afford any casualties
不管是人类还是汽车人！
human or bot.
我已经失去两个老搭档了
I've already lost two seasoned partners.
我不想在名单上再添一个菜鸟
I don't need a rookie on my scorecard.
绝不会的
Not gonna happen.
我以精英卫队的荣誉起誓
Elite guardsman's honor.
慢着 你失去过两个搭档？
Wait. You lost two partners?
你又破译了一组铁堡遗物的坐标？
You have decoded the next set of Iacon coordinates.
干得漂亮 声波！
Excellent work, Soundwave.
哈 人类还挺热衷把这些巨石堆到咱们的遗物上 是吧？
Ha. Nice of the humans to pile all these rocks on top of our relic, huh?
不言而喻 是吧？
Pretty much spells things out, doesn't it?
来 帮我移开这个！
Come on. Help me move this.
古代人类八成把终极之钥当成众神赐予的礼物了
The ancient humans must have thought the Omega key was a gift from the gods.
某种意义上讲 他们没错
And, in a sense, they weren't wrong.
快点 交出遗物
The relic... now!
二打一 我们能搞定他
Two against one. We can take him.
救护车 打开环陆桥 快！
Ratchet, ground bridge, now!
烟幕！
Smokescreen!
这次铁堡送来的又是怎样的宝物？
What manner of treasure did Iacon send us this time?
我可以现在就把你切成两半
I would slice you in two right now...
但我还想要你传个口信
but I need you to deliver a message.
告诉擎天柱 他要是想要遗物
Tell Optimus Prime that if he wants this relic
就亲自来抢！
he must come and claim it himself!
接着烟幕就…消失了
And then Smokescreen was just... gone...
好像烟消云散一般
like he turned to dust.
可怜的娃
Poor kid.
阿尔茜 别太自责
Arcee, do not blame yourself.
当时你也命在旦夕
It could just as easily have been you.
要我说我们这就去扒下威震天一块皮下来！
I say we go claim a piece of Megatron's miserable, metal hide!
不行 今天我们已经失去了一位战友了
No. We have already lost another one of our own today.
我不能再让任何人冒险
I will not risk more lives.
根据阿尔茜的所见
Given what Arcee witnessed
可以推断威震天拥有一件与星辰剑威力相当的武器
it stands to reason that Megatron now possesses might to equal the Star Saber
也就是说 只有我有可能夺回终极之钥
which means only I have a chance of recovering the Omega key.
塞博特恩的命运全指望它了
The fate of Cybertron rests upon its retrieval.
不管威震天明不明白
Whether Megatron knows it or not.
来拿你的战利品吧 擎天柱
Claim your prize, Optimus.
只要你拿得到
If you can.
火种源在上 威震天
By the Allspark, Megatron.
你做了什么？
What have you done?!
这个吗？
This.
它为我赢得了一些优势
I find it affords me certain advantages
比如使用卓天越之锤
such as the use of the Forge of Solus Prime.
这是我的第一件作品
My first creation
以宇宙大帝之血铸就
fashioned from the very blood of Unicron.
我称之为暗黑星辰剑
I call it the Dark Star Saber...
你也可以称它 屠戮领袖之剑！
slayer of Primes, if you will.
最终我们还是接受了命运的安排 擎天柱
At last we take our rightful places, Optimus.
逆天成神！我们挥舞着宇宙的力量！
As gods, wielding the power of the cosmos!
我只不过是个战士 威震天
I am but a soldier, Megatron
而你 只不过是被自我扭曲的妄想所囚禁的狂徒！
and you are a prisoner of your own twisted delusions!
我的暗黑星辰剑今晚已经啜饮过一个火种的鲜血
My Dark Star Saber has tasted one spark tonight.
它还渴望着吞噬一个领袖的生命！
It still thirsts for that of a Prime!
大幕将落 正如我所预见的一样！
And so it ends, just as I envisioned
我要用你的头颅来祭我的战利品！
with your head beside my new trophy.
哦 你是说这个？
Oh, you mean this?
谁找到归谁！
Finders keepers.
烟幕 退后！
Smokescreen, fall back!
救护车 打开环陆桥！
Ratchet, ground bridge!
不！
No!
没打中
Missed us.
逃吧 擎天柱 尽管逃吧！
Run, Optimus, run!
这些铁堡的小玩具救不了你的
Those trinkets from Iacon will not save you
因为现在我拥有了能斩断整个世界的力量！
not when I now possess the power to tear this world apart!
烟幕？
Smokescreen?!
以及第一个终极之钥！
And Omega key number one.
可 这是怎么…我是说 我亲眼看见…
But... how? I mean, I saw you...
我 呃 之前又“借”走了相位仪！
I, uh, decided to borrow the Phase shifter.
又一次！
Again?
幸亏我拿了
Good thing, too.
那阵冲击波简直像铁球一样砸在我身上！
The wave from the blast hit me like a wrecking ball.
一定是那冲击激活了相位仪
The impact must have activated the shifter.
我不知道昏迷了多久
I don't know how long I was unconscious
不过当我好不容易出来的时候
but when I made my way back outside
擎天柱和威震天正在进行一场史诗般的战斗！
Optimus and Megatron were deep in an epic throwdown.
我只是瞅准时机 做了该做的事…
I waited for the right moment to make my move.
你有进步
You're learning.
那么我能留着它吗？
So, can I keep it?
我是说 这玩意儿对我来说太好使了！
I mean, it is really working out for me.
好吧 好吧
Fine, fine.
好哎！我也有专属武器了！
Yes! Signature weapon!
你得到了你的武器 擎天柱却失去了他的
You got yours. Optimus lost his.
力量的天平又向另一方倾斜了
The balance of power shifted again.
虽说他仅能使用一天先祖留下的神力
While he may have wielded the power of the ancients for only one day
但擎天柱不依靠外力 仍旧是最伟大的战士
Optimus does not require it to be the mightiest of warriors.